<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-21T02:15:43+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Pramod Panchagnula</title><subtitle>I am a Product guy from a data background. I previously co-founded Scale Labs. I mainly write about business, tech, movies, and books. You can reach me on Twitter.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How I Read (Part 1)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2020/07/21/how-i-read.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I Read (Part 1)" /><published>2020-07-21T00:23:48+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-21T00:23:48+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2020/07/21/how-i-read</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2020/07/21/how-i-read.html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright. Yeah. That’s okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;«cracks knuckles»
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Until I feared I would lose it, I never loved to read. One does not love breathing.- H Lee. My hero, overall champion person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I don’t love reading. Fiction has been a fairly small percentage of what I read, and aren’t all those quotes about reading only about fiction anyway? I don’t love reading. Love or hate is not the lens I would approach reading with. It’s what I do. I need it, and not in the romantic sense of the word. It’s mostly pragmatic. I don’t know how to do a lot of things, I don’t know how to think a lot of things, I don’t know how to feel a lot of things. Reading is what solves these little inconveniences for me. Reading to me is all those cliches that a 1860s wife was supposed to be. A sibling, a parent, a teacher, a mentor, a friend, a lover. Most of all, reading is the constant companion, an ever available escape when everything else invariably gets overwhelming.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was 17 at a college that I thought I was too good for, and which turned out to be the other way around, I met an amazing senior who said something that influenced my reading for almost the entire decade that followed -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Why do you read fiction? Fiction is for elevated minds that want to relax? What have you fucking accomplished to deserve it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fair enough, I guess. As someone that’s always been into trying to over-optimise his life by gobbling up non-fiction, this advice felt like Jesus’s blood or whatever. I read two or three fiction books a year. The best. All my favourites till date. I guess the greed of consuming the very best literature to make up for the lack of volume pays off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut to 27 and reading fiction is a very natural choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I read fiction to be destroyed by Murakami’s words. &lt;br /&gt;
I read fiction to be washed over by the genius and the tragedy that Fitzgerald’s life was.  &lt;br /&gt;
I read fiction to be able to feel at least an iota as much as Sylvia Plath did at her numbest.&lt;br /&gt;
I read fiction because Kurt Vonnegut isn’t a legend to me, but a best friend who thinks like I do.&lt;br /&gt;
I read fiction because Douglas Adams is a master showing kid me the ropes of what is possible.&lt;br /&gt;
I read fiction because Amy Hempel makes me feel more worthless than a Wisdom tooth with her word economy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yeah, reading fiction is a very natural choice. It is a natural choice because I would choose being poor and feel everything I could feel and think everything I could to being successful and shallow. Success can wait. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Do you read everything you’re supposed to read? Do you feel everything you’re supposed to feel? Do you think everything you’re supposed to think?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts" /><summary type="html">This is my first blog post.</summary></entry></feed>